Thompson Eregha

Software Engineer

Lagos, Nigeria

<u>2347064836051</u>, <u>thompsoneregha00@gmail.com</u>, <u>linkedin.com/in/thompsoneregha</u>, github.com/Godbrand0

Adaptable Software Engineer with 2 years of experience designing and implementing innovative frontend solutions in Social media, Landing page and e-commerce. Specializing in crafting user-friendly applications and web pages, I excel in enhancing the overall user experience through collaborative problem-solving.

Experience

OCTOBER 2024 - OCTOBER 2024

Energy Talent AI, Abuja, Nigeria – Frontend Developer (Contract)

Tools – Reactjs, Tailwind CSS

- Implemented an infinite marquee of and team images in the hero section, creating a dynamic, continuously scrolling effect to capture user attention and convey a strong brand presence, showcasing talent diversity, contributing to an inviting and professional first impression on the landing page.
- Implemented breakpoints and flexible grid layouts using Tailwind CSS, ensuring a consistent user experience that enhances accessibility and engagement across a diverse range of devices.

AUGUST 2024 - PRESENT

NeTuArk, West Bangal, India – *Co-founder, Frontend engineer*

Tools – Javascript, Firebase, Tailwind CSS

- Contributed to the Chat Room feature by optimizing functionality and addressing bugs, significantly speeding up student conversations and improving real-time engagement.
- Utilized Firebase Firestore to store chat data, including messages and user profiles, enabling dynamic data updates and seamless user interactions.
- Worked on the Feeds platform, managing replies to posts, fixing issues, and optimizing performance. Enhanced user experience by accelerating how students connect with new people through posts.

Grand Coast Hotels, Ondo, Nigeria – Frontend Developer (Contract)

Tools – javascript, CSS

- Contributed to Grand Coast's latest website launch, boosting online visibility and engagement by 25% through SEO optimization and performance improvements.
- Optimized mobile responsiveness to provide seamless access for users on mobile and tablet devices, ensuring usability at any time.
- Focused on a streamlined user experience by implementing intuitive navigation, easy-to-read product details, and efficient page loading.

Projects & Volunteer Experience

FEBRUARY 2024 - MARCH 2024

Grocify food web Application – *Software Developer*

Tools - Javascript, TailwindCSS, Firebase.

- Integrated Firebase Authentication for secure user sign-in, log-out, and user verification, providing a streamlined and secure login experience.
- Leveraged Tailwind CSS to create a visually appealing, responsive design that adapts seamlessly across devices.
- Implemented accessibility best practices to make the webpage inclusive, user-friendly, mobile responsive and compatible across devices.

OCTOBER 2024 - DECEMBER 2024

Getajob Landing Page – Software developer

Tools – React js, CSS

- Applied precise font sizes, styles, and colors to design a visually appealing web page, while
 utilizing margins, widths, and transitions to add subtle interactivity and enhance user
 engagement.
- Built reusable and scalable React functional components, leveraging hooks for state management and performance optimization, with a mobile-first approach to ensure responsiveness across devices.

Skills

Tools/Programming languages

- Javascript
- React.js
- Firebase
- CSS, Tailwind CSS, SASS
- UI frameworks

Certificates

Responsive Web Design – FreecodeCamp; June, 2024

Jobberman Soft-Skills Training - June, 2023

Education

HIEM Weldios university, cotonou, Benin Republic – *Mechanical and Production Engineering;* 2023

Relevant Coursework – fundamentals (v-Basic, C++, MATLAB), AutoCAD designs

Interests

- -Software Engineering
- -Art
- -Reading
- -photography